Guide to the Yale Record Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Record, records
1921-1948
RU 519
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.5
The records consist of correspondence, manuscripts, legal and financial papers, and cartoons documenting the Yale Record.
Yale Record
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 40 (YRG 40), Records of Yale clubs, societies, and organizations.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by record type.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale Record, a student publication, was established in 1872.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, manuscripts, legal and financial papers, and cartoons documenting the Yale Record.
Yale record; College student newspapers and periodicals; Yale University -- Students -- Caricatures and cartoons; Yale University -- Students
- Records, Accession 19ND-A-407
  - Correspondence
    - 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 5)
    - 1927 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1928 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1929 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1930 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1933-1936 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Manuscripts, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Manuscripts, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Pictures, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Contracts
    - 1927 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - 1928 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - 1928 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - 1929 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - 1932 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - 1933 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - 1934 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Receipts, 1924-1936 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Ledger Sheets
    - 1922 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - 1925 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - 1926 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - 1927 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - 1928 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - 1931-1932 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - 1932-1933 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Cash Books
    - 1928 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - 1929 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - 1930 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - 1931 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - 1932 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - 1933 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Building Fund Incorporated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Board Record of Checks
    - 1922 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - 1925 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - 1927 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - 1929-1930 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - 1930 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - 1931-1932 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - 1933-1936 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Rough copy of "Tissue Issue", 1943 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Rough copy of "We'll Miss You Issue", 1943 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Cartoons, Circa 1940s (Box 8, Folder 51 - 57)
  - Cartoons, Circa 1940s (Box 9, Folder 58 - 61)
  - Oversized cartoons, Circa 1940s (Box 10A–10E)
  - Oversized cartoons, Circa 1940s (Box 11A–11F)